(217) 550-2241

MAURICE LAM

™ me@mauricelam.com

Full Name: Yuk Yin Maurice LAM

University: University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

Major: Computer Science Class: Senior GPA: 3.98

PROFILE

I am software developer and a computer science student who is deeply passionate in software development and obsessed with delivering the perfect user experience. I constantly look for challenges by initiating my own projects like mobile app development, website design, startup and research.

- Interested in front-end programming for web or mobile apps
- Designer & developer of *Transit CUMTD*, an Android app with over 3500 users
- ▶ 2 other Android apps, 3 Chrome and Safari browser extensions

EXPERIENCE

INTERNSHIP

Software Intern - Apple Inc.

Summer 2012

Software intern at Apple iOS team. Responsible for improving a JavaScript framework aimed to streamline development of web content on multiple platforms. Worked closely with JavaScript, CSS, HTML and other advanced web technologies.

STARTUP

Developer - HKStockPulse

2011-2012

Developer in the startup HKStockPulse, which is a web platform for stock enthusiasts and financial professionals to exchange and share their views. Mainly responsible for developing a mobile web app for the platform.

RESEARCH PROJECT

Front-end Developer - YouPivot

2010-2012

Front-end developer for YouPivot, a research project aimed to reinvent the way we approach our personal digital history. Responsible for developing the front-end, a Google Chrome extension, and designing user experience for future versions.

WEBSITE MANAGEMENT

Webmaster - Illini Chinese Christian Fellowship; UIUC

2011-present

Webmaster responsible for designing, authoring and maintaining the website for the fellowship. Other duties include managing member information database and other digital assets.

DESIGN EXPERIENCE

Chief Designer - School Editorial Board; St. Joseph's College, Hong Kong

2008-2009

Responsible for designing publications such as the school gazette and school magazine. Also involved in working with printing companies to ensure perfect realization of the design. Worked with graphics software such as Adobe Fireworks, Illustrator and Photoshop.

AWARDS / HONORS

GOOGLE GSA DEVELOPMENT COMPETITION

TapToPrint - 1st place - Jan 2013

MOZILLA DESIGN CHALLENGE

HomeTab - Top 10 design - Winter 2009

DEAN'S LIST

Fall 2010, Spring 2011, Fall 2011, Spring 2012

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS

*Urbana-Champaign, Illinois — Aug 2010 - Dec 2013*Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Proficient Java, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, PHP

Basic C, C++, Objective C, Python, Ruby, OCaml, MySQL